

Lara Ramos Poblet

WEB DEVELOPER

Web developer with experience as a Frontend Developer and a background in social work with a focus on disability. Committed to merging technology and social awareness to create web solutions with a positive impact on people's lives. SKILLS

linkedin.com/in/lararamospoblet

Lrpoblet@gmail.com

Madrid, Spain

Click here to view my portfolio

EXPERIENCE



FRONTEND WEB DEVELOPER

Kairós Digital Solutions S.L.

March 2023 - August 2023

- · Development of web components in Native JavaScript (Vanilla JS) using LitElement.
- Improvement of accessibility (WCAG 2.1) and performance of Kairós' commercial website.
- Testing with Jest and Cypress.
- Use of CI/CD pipelines, Docker and docker-compose.
- · Project development using React and Styled-components.
- · Version control with Git.
- · API calls.

SOCIAL WORKER



Asociación Española de síndrome de Rett January 2019 - September 2022





Asociación AMI-3





























Spanish Sign Language: B2

EDUCATION

INTERFACES AND USER EXPERIENCE (UI/UX)



Nowe Creative | October 2023 - November 2023

Analysis, design, prototyping and validation of UX/UI using Figma, Adobe XD, Sketch app and Marvel app.

WEB DEVELOPMENT



Generación K | March 2023 - April 2023

Git, DevOps (Docker), Web Accessibility, JavaScript (ES6+), Jest, LitElement, Cypress and Firebase.



Adalab | September 2022 - December 2022

Layout: HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Bootstrap, mobile first and responsive design.

JavaScript (ES6) and third-party web services (APIs).

Version control with Git.

Creation of SPAs with React.

Node.js, ExpressJS and SQL/SQLite Management of Slack, Github, VS Code, Gulp, Terminal, Linter, Zeplin...



MASTER IN SUPPORT FOR PEOPLE WITH **DISABILITIES AND/OR DEVELOPMENT** UAM-Plena Inclusión 2015 - 2017

WEB DEVELOPMENT



Escuela de Organización Industrial 2016

Layout: HTML, CSS, JavaScript. Bootstrap, jQuery and AngularJS.



DEGREE IN SOCIAL WORK UCM 2009 - 2013



December 2016 - December 2018

RECENT COURSES (view more in portfolio)



ACCESIBLE CODE

The A11Y Collective

August 2023 - Currently

REACT HOOKS + TESTING



Lemoncode

May 2023



WEB ACCESIBILITY



February 2023

Lara Ramos Poblet

WEB DEVELOPER

- linkedin.com/in/lararamospoblet
- <u>Lrpoblet@gmail.com</u>
- Madrid, Spain

ABOUT ME

I am a professional in constant evolution, with experience in Social Work and specialization in disability area. My interest in technology and innovation led me to an exciting transition into the world of Web Development.

Currently, I am training in user interfaces and experience (UX/UI), web accessibility and in TDD.

In my last work experience, I have had the opportunity to work as a Frontend Developer at Kairós Digital Solutions S.L., where I have created reusable JavaScript components with LitElement and improved the accessibility and performance of their commercial website. I have also applied tests with Jest and Cypress and have worked on continuous integration and deployments with Docker, among other fundamental tasks. In addition to my experience with the mentioned technologies, I have also worked on several projects using React as my main framework and SASS for styles. In the past, I have also done projects with AngularJS and jQuery, so I would have no problem picking it up and updating myself on its latest versions.

My ability to **adapt**, attention to **detail**, **curiosity** and **proactivity** are qualities that I have developed and perfected throughout my career. Additionally, my background in social work has given me a unique and **empathetic** perspective on the importance of technology in society, enhancing my understanding of **community needs** and **problem solving**.

My current goal is to merge my technical skills with my empathy and social perspective to create inclusive and accessible digital solutions. I firmly believe that technology can make a difference in people's lives and I am excited to be part of that change.

Click here to view my portfolio